Contact

+237674128573 (Mobile) tanoparksonsilencer@gmail.c om

www.linkedin.com/in/danielparkson-tano (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Ionic Framework

Bootstrap

Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)

Certifications

Introduction to Front-End Development

Google Data Analytics Capstone: Complete a Case Study

HTML and CSS in depth

Google Data Analytics Certificate

Ask Questions to Make Data-Driven Decisions

Daniel Parkson Tano

Python Developer | Django | ReactJS | Data Analyst | Full-Stack developer | Web Developer | JavaScript | React Native | Mobile Dev Yaounde, Centre, Cameroon

Summary

A versatile individual with 5 years of experience building web applications with Django, HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, as well as building web applications with JavaScript frontend framework which make use of HTTP requests using the RESTful API built with Django Rest Framework.

Experience

Tantorial
Full-stack Developer
July 2018 - Present (4 years 7 months)
Yaounde

Gebeya Inc.
Back End Developer
August 2022 - Present (6 months)
Yaoundé, Cameroon

Gebeya Talent, freelance Python Backend developer with Gebeya.

UNU-WIDER - United Nations University World Institute for Development Economics Research Research Assistant March 2020 - Present (2 years 11 months)

- Perform analysis on evaluation of Donor Support to public financial management (PFM) reform in developing countries worked on data about donations to developing countries by bilateral and multilateral (UN) donors from 1900 to 2018
- Worked on data about foreign aid and support to developing countries.
- Developed Key Performance Indicators to monitor tax, revenue, and foreign aid to developing countries with 97% accuracy
- Conducted research on data expressing interest in foreign aid and domestic taxation, tax structure, economic growth, and development, taxation, non-tax revenue, and democracy, electoral competitiveness, political budget cycles,

and taxation in developing countries from ICTD UNU-WIDER Government Revenue Dataset

- Extracted and performed analysis on the level of democracy enjoyed by an average global citizen, electoral autocracy, level of political regime corruption, and judicial and legislative the constraint for developing countries from the Varieties of Democracy (V-DEM) datasets.
- Study government expenditure on health, education, agriculture, import, export, and natural resource as a percentage of countries' GDP for developing countries.
- Writing codes in R and Python to perform statistical analysis and visualization for various datasets such as GRD UNU-WIDER, Data extracted from world development indicators, Country-specific estimates of taxes and constraints, and revenue.
- Completed democracy index analysis, resulting in a 21% increase in efficiency and submission rate.

Ministry of Basic and Senior Secondary Education Science Teacher October 2019 - Present (3 years 4 months)

Yaoundé, Cameroon

- Created and maintained a welcoming, friendly, engaging, and nurturing classroom environment where all students felt comfortable.
- Established classroom and practical lessons and enforced them fairly and effectively.
- Developed rigorous lesson plans and lectures and prepared students for quizzes and tests.
- Graded papers, lessons, tests, quizzes, and other assignments, relaying information to parents and the school board when necessary.
- Decreased student fail rate by 32% in the 2020–2021 school year in classrooms with over $\,$

30 students

Imobbis

Django Developer

January 2019 - September 2022 (3 years 9 months)

Yaoundé, Cameroon

Built backend API with Django rest framework for interaction between frontend end built with React Native with firebase

Supervised 4 colleagues to ensure adherence to quality standards and proper work procedures

Designed and configured database and back-end applications and programs.

Coded test programs and evaluated existing engineering processes.

Handled programming tasks and maintained 3 internal APIs with a high success rate (97%) in product update deployment.

Worked on high-impact projects such as content recommendation systems, delivering solutions with lower than 20% code churn.

Developed a marketing lead MySQL database, collecting, categorizing, and filtering leads from various stakeholders

Configure and manage firebase user authentication, cloud messaging, and notification

for all company projects with a success rate and deployment time of 94%

MBTek Solutions

Full-stack Developer

June 2021 - April 2022 (11 months)

Yaoundé, Cameroon

- Handled programming tasks and maintained 3 internal APIs with a high success rate (97%) in product update deployment.
- Worked on high-impact projects such as content recommendation systems, delivering solutions with lower than 20% code churn.
- Developed a marketing lead database model, collecting, categorizing, and filtering leads from various stakeholders
- Build frontend UI with an ionic framework which was widely appreciated by the company leader.
- Configure and manage firebase user authentication, cloud messaging, and notification for all company projects with a success rate and deployment time of 94%.
- Built backend API with Django rest framework for interaction between frontend end built with Ionic framework.
- Supervised 4 colleagues to ensure adherence to quality standards and proper work procedures
- Designed and configured database and back-end applications and programs.
- Coded test programs and evaluated existing engineering processes.

Education

University of Yaounde 1

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (October 2022 - July 2023)

Higher Teacher Training College, university of maroua

Diploma of Education, Mathematics and Computer Science · (October 2016 - August 2019)